Guide to the Iron Clad Agreement Records, 1973-1989 CTC.1990.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Playscripts, 1976-1989; II.
  - Whitney by James Krut - ICA 4541 (Folder 13)
  - Wright Brothers (Script Fragment) by M.M. Melozzi - ICA 4542 (Folder 14)
  - Young Peoples Concert with Pittsburgh Symphony Orchestra - ICA 4543 (Folder 15)
- Photographs, 1976-1982; III.
  Contains photographs and negatives of productions, actors, rehearsals, publicity material, and contact sheets. Materials are in alphabetical order by subject. Existing labels on the photographs have been accepted. The details of many of the photographs were supplied by the donors. Please note that the Iron Clad Agreement founder Julia Royall is citied throughout the finding aid as Julia Swoyer, her name at the time.
  - The Amazing American Idea Factory (Box 24, Folder 1)
    Photograph includes K.W. Hutton, Christopher Josephs, James Krut, M.M. Melozzi, and D'Arcy Webb. This folder also includes negatives.
  - Art/Work (Folder 2)
    Photographs include K.W. Hutton, Larry John Meyers, and Ann Beigel. Photographs are by Julia R. Swoyer. This folder also includes negatives.
  - Barnum, February 1978 (Folder 3)
    Photographs include Nancy Friedman and James Krut.
  - Burbank, February 1978 (Folder 4)
    Photograph includes K.W. Hutton.
  - Clepper, Gregory (Folder 5)
  - Creativity with Bill Moyers (Folder 6)
    Photographs include Maya Angelou, John Huston, Norman Lear, Bill Moyers, and Samson Raphaelson.
  - Eastman, February 1978 (Folder 7)
    Photographs include Nancy Friedman, K.W. Hutton, and James Krut.
  - Echoes from the Valley, 1984 (Folder 8)
    Photographs include Julia Swoyer and Major Road Theater. This folder also includes negatives.
  - Edison, 1976-1978 (Folder 9)
    Photographs include Nancy Friedman, K.W. Hutton, and James Krut. This folder also includes negatives.
  - Edison - Lincoln Center Holiday Festival, 1982 (Folder 10)
    Photographs include Ann Beigel, Judith Ferrenbach, David Garfield, and K.W. Hutton.
  - Father K, 1979-1980 (Folder 11)
    Photographs include K.W. Hutton. This folder also includes negatives.
  - 57 By Two (Folder 12)
    Photograph includes Mark Harlow and K.W. Hutton. Photograph by Stan Sukolsky.
  - Ford, February 1978 (Folder 13)
  - Friedman, Nancy, 1978 (Folder 14)
  - Gift to America, 1981 (Folder 15)
    Photograph includes Katherine Ames, Ann Beigel, Doug Mertz, and Larry John Meyers.
  - Gilded Age of Invention (Folder 16)
    Photographs include K.W. Hutton, J. Krut, M.M. Melozzi, and Christopher Josephs.
  - Gov't Owned Apples with Lovelace Theatre, 1978 (Folder 17)
    Photographs include David Crocker, K.W. Hutton, James Krut, and Fred Michael.
  - Hutton, K. Wilson (Folder 18)
    This folder also includes negatives.
  - Interchangeable Parts (Folder 19)
    Photographs include Katherine Ames, Ann Beigel, Doug Mertz, and Larry John Meyers. This folder also includes negatives.
  - Iron Clad Agreement - Administrative Staff, 1981 (Folder 20)
    Photograph includes Tom Hearn, general manager and director, Geoffrey Hitch, director, and Julia Swoyer, executive producer.
  - Iron Clad Agreement - Group photo, August 1976 (Folder 21)
    Photographs include Nancy Friedman, Elan Garonzik, K.W. Hutton, James Krut, and Julia Swoyer.
  - Iron Clad Agreement - Group photos, 1977 (Folder 22)
    Photograph includes Nancy Friedman, K.W. Hutton, James Krut, and Julia Swoyer.
  - Iron Clad Agreement - Group photos, February 1978 (Folder 23)
    These publicity photos include Nancy Friedman, K.W. Hutton, James Krut, and Julia Swoyer. This folder also includes negatives.
  - Iron Clad Agreement - Group photo, 1981 (Folder 24)
  - Iron Clad Agreement - Publicity photos (Folder 25)
    Photographs include Ramona Fischer Dowiak, Nancy Friedman, Mark Harlow, K.W. Hutton, Christopher Josephs, James Krut, M.M. Melozzi, Doug Merz, and Julia Swoyer. This folder also includes negatives.
  - Josephs, Christopher (Folder 26)
  - Krut, James (Folder 27)
  - Labor Trilogy (Folder 28)
    Photograph includes Ron Hankison, director, Mark Harlow, James Krut, and K.W. Wilson.
  - Major Road Theatre Company (Folder 29)
    Photographs include Liz Humphrey-Williams, Phil Hearne, Sue Betts, and Kevin Stamp.
  - Melozzi, M. M. (Folder 30)
  - My Dear Sisters (Folder 31)
    Photograph includes M.M. Melozzi and Dorothy Rosenberg.
  - Ourselves Alone, 1976-1981 (Folder 32)
    Photographs are of K. Wilson Hutton as playwright Sean O'Casey. This folder also includes negatives.
  - Out of This Furnace, December 1977 (Folder 33)
    Photographs include Ramona Fischer, Nancy Friedman, K.W. Hutton, James Krut, and Cathy Rakow. This folder also includes negatives.
  - Penitentiary (Boise, Idaho) - Research trip (Folder 34)
  - Pittsburgh (Folder 35)
    This folder of negatives has several exterior images from around Pittsburgh.
  - Rehearsals/Performances - Unidentified (Folder 36)
    This folder contains negatives only.
  - Scott, Harold, 1978-1979 (Folder 37)
  - Search for Haven (Folder 38)
    Photograph includes Katherine Ames and Doug Mertz. This folder also includes negatives.
  - Swoyer, Julia, 1977-1978 (Folder 39)
  - Thomas A. Edison (Folder 40)
    Photographs include Mark Harlow, K.W. Hutton, James Krut, and M.M. Melozzi. This folder also includes negatives.
  - Three Rivers Arts Festival with Lovelace Marionette Theatre (Folder 41)
  - Toymakers (Folder 42)
    Photographs include Doug Mertz, Larry John Meyers, and Ann Beigel. This folder also includes negatives.
  - Toymakers - Lincoln Center Holiday Festival, 1981 (Folder 43)
  - Virgins and Dynamos (Folder 44)
    Photographs include J. Holt, K.W. Hutton, Susan Wilder, and G. Weinberg. This folder also includes negatives.
  - Webb, D'Arcy, 1978-1979 (Folder 45)
  - Westinghouse, April 1978 (Folder 46)
    Photographs include Nancy Friedman, K.W. Hutton, James Krut, and Julia Swoyer.
  - Youngstown Ohio, 1980 (Folder 47)
    Photographs include K.W. Hutton and James Krut.
- Slides, 1977-1981; IV.
  Includes both slides taken for publicity, etc. and those used in a production. The same standards for attributions were followed as with photographs.
  - American Wind Symphony Performances, 1980 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Art/Work, 1981 (Folder 2)
  - Bill Moyer's 'Creativity' the Horace Mann Theatre at Columbia University, 1980 (Folder 3)
  - Gov't Owned Apples (Folder 4)
  - Group Shots (Folder 5)
  - Hartwood Acres, 1980 (Folder 6)
  - Library Tour - with Dr. R. Teare (Folder 7)
  - On Tour (Folder 8)
  - On Tour - Warm Up (Folder 9)
  - On Tour - with Dr. R. Teare (Folder 10)
  - Open House at the Wilkins School in Swissvale (Folder 11)
  - Out of This Furnace, 1977-1978 (Folder 12)
  - Out of This Furnace - Aliquippa, 1977-1978 (Folder 13)
  - Out of This Furnace - Production Slides, 1977-1978 (Folder 14)
  - St. Nicholas Murals in Millvale (Folder 15)
  - Summer Program (Folder 16)
  - School Performances (Folder 17)
  - Swissvale at the Wilkins School - Office/rehearsal space (Folder 18)
  - Unidentified (Folder 19)
  - Westinghouse video stills, 1981 (Folder 20)
- Audio Recordings, 1975-1984; V.
  Both cassette and reel recordings of performances, advertisements, and rehearsals. Materials are arranged alphabetically by title.
  - Cassette Tapes, 1975-1984; 1.
    The audio cassettes in this series contain entire performances, songs, or music from Iron Clad Agreement productions. They are arranged alphabetically by title.
    - Amazing American Idea Factory (Box 26, Tape 1)
    - Art/Work - Music (Tape 2)
    - Art/Work at Carlow College, January 30, 1981 (Tape 3)
    - Arts Alive, May 1977 (Tape 4)
    - Barnum at Old Post Office Museum, July 10, 1977 (Tape 5)
    - Burbank at the Theater Association of Pennsylvania Conference, April 2, 1978 (Tape 6)
    - Burbank - Songs (Tape 7)
    - Carnegie at the Wilkins School, November 9, 1978 (Tape 8)
    - Carnegie - Pittsburgh production, May 7-19, 1976 (Tape 9)
    - Carnegie, July 4, 1976 (Tape 10)
    - Carnegie - Copy of recording of Edinburgh production at Royal Lyceum), 1975 (Tape 11-12)
    - Dynamite! - Rehearsal, July 21, 1978 (Tape 13)
    - Gilded Age of Invention at the Federation of Telephone Workers in Penn State University, June 14, 1978 (Tape 13)
    - Dynamite! at the Federation of Telephone Workers (Tape 14)
    - Eastman - Rehearsal, August 11, 1977 (Tape 15)
    - Echoes in America - Tour of Rhode Island, Connecticut, North Carolina, South Carolina, March 1984 (Tape 16)
    - Edison, November 6, 1976 (Tape 17)
    - Edison, October 1976 (Tape 18)
    - Christmas Play, December 1976 (Tape 18)
    - Edison at Lincoln Center Holiday Festival, December 17, 1982 (Tape 19)
    - Edison at Carnegie Mellon University, October 31, 1979 (Tape 20)
    - Songs & Speeches of Labor at Linden Hall for United Steelworkers, October 1979 (Tape 20)
    - Eli Whitney - Music (Tape 21)
    - Evening With Eileen at the Mattress Factory, November 13, 1980 (Tape 22)
    - Father K at the First Unitarian Church in Pittsburgh, December 14, 1979 (Tape 23)
    - 57 by Two (Tape 24)
    - 57 by Two / Grimke Dialect (Tape 25)
    - Ford, April 1, 1977 (Tape 26)
    - Ford – Songs by Robert Nesius (Tape 27)
    - Gift to America at St. Nicholas Croatian Catholic Church in Millvale, April 22, 1981 (Tape 28)
    - Gilded Age of Invention at Magee Women’s Hospital in Pittsburgh, April 26, 1979 (Tape 29)
    - Gilded Age of Invention and Whitney reading at the Eli Whitney Museum in New Haven, June 29, 1979 (Tape 29)
    - Gov't Owned Apples - Preview, June 2, 1978 (Tape 30-31)
    - Guggenheim - Rehearsal (Tape 32)
    - Hasta Cuando?, 1987 (Tape 33)
    - Homestead Labor Day, September 3, 1981 (Tape 34)
    - Interchangeable Parts, September 28, 1980 (Tape 35)
    - Labor Radio Series (Tape 36)
    - Labor Song demo tape (Tape 37)
    - My Dear Sisters at Clemson University, June 6, 1980 (Box 27, Tape 38)
    - Ourselves Alone at Carlow College, December 7, 1980 (Tape 39)
    - Out of This Furnace - Song tape, 1978-1979 (Tape 40)
    - Out of This Furnace at Carnegie Music Hall in Homestead, November 30, 1977 (Tape 41)
    - Out of This Furnace - Mike and Mary, December 7, 1977 (Tape 42)
    - Out of This Furnace for United Steelworkers in Aliquippa, March 16, 1978 (Tape 43)
    - Out of This Furnace at Carnegie Music Hall in Homestead – Dobie, November 30, 1978 (Tape 44)
    - Out of This Furnace - Mike & Dobie (Tape 45)
    - Out of This Furnace – Songs (Tape 46)
    - Out of This Furnace - Act I at Allegheny College in Meadville, January 25, 1979 (Tape 47)
    - Out of This Furnace - Act II at Allegheny College in Meadville, January 25, 1979 (Tape 48)
    - Prologue Play, August 1976 (Tape 48)
    - Sea-Change - Music by Barbara Demashek (Tape 50)
    - Search for Haven at the Carnegie Museum of Art in Pittsburgh, May 17, 1981 (Tape 51)
    - Spirit of Mercy at Carlow College, June 24, 1981 (Tape 52)
    - Toymakers at Carlow College, December 14, 1980 (Tape 53)
    - Toymakers at Lincoln Center Holiday Festival, December 1981 (Tape 54)
    - Toymakers – Music by Robert Nesius, 1981 (Tape 55)
    - Under the Stars and Bars at Carlow College, December 6, 1980 (Tape 56)
    - Virgins and Dynamos at Carlow College - rehearsal, October 2, 1981 (Tape 57)
    - Westinghouse, December 1976 (Tape 58)
    - Workshop - Hong Kong, May 20, 1984 (Tape 59-60)
    - Workshop - Hong Kong, May 19, 1984 (Tape 61)
    - Workshop - Tai Wo Hau Estate Resident (Tape 62)
    - WQED review, 1978-1979 (Tape 63)
  - Resource Tapes, 2.
    This series contains audio cassettes that were used as resources when planning the company's productions. For the most part they contain fragments of speeches by various historical figures throughout the twentieth century. These cassettes are noted as being copies from Michigan State University.
    - AFL-CIO Merger/UAW Split (Tape 64)
    - Early Social Issues and Labor (Tape 65)
    - Labor and Civil Rights (Tape 66)
    - Labor and Communism (Tape 67)
    - Labor and Foreign Policy (Tape 68)
    - Labor and Organizing (Tape 69)
    - Labor and Taft-Hartley (Tape 70)
    - Labor and the War Effort (Tape 71)
    - McClellan Committee and Teamster Expulsion (Tape 72)
  - Audio Reels, 1980; 3.
    This series contains audio tape on reels. The content of the audio is either audio recordings or entire performances, some of which were aired on the radio, or advertisements for the Iron Clad Agreement's productions. Some of the audio reels are master recordings.
    - 57 by Two, April 9, 1980 (Reel 1)
    - 57 by Two - promo, March 13, 1980 (Reel 2)
    - Guggenheim, 1978 (Reel 3)
    - Labor Trilogy (I): Homestead, 1980 (Reel 4)
    - Labor Trilogy (I): Depression, 1980 (Reel 5)
    - Labor Trilogy (I): Responsibility, 1980 (Reel 6)
    - Labor Trilogy (II): Homestead, 1980 (Reel 7)
    - Labor Trilogy (II): Depression, 1980 (Reel 8)
    - Labor Trilogy (II): Responsibility, 1980 (Reel 9)
    - Labor Trilogy (III): Homestead, 1980 (Reel 10)
    - Labor Trilogy (III): Depression, 1980 (Reel 11)
    - Labor Trilogy (III): Responsibility, 1980 (Reel 12)
    - Labor Trilogy (IV): Homestead, 1980 (Reel 13)
    - Labor Trilogy (IV): Depression and Responsibility, 1980 (Reel 14)
    - My Dear Sisters - Promo, March 13, 1980 (Reel 15)
    - My Dear Sisters, June 6, 1980 (Reel 16)
    - Unidentified (Reel 17-18)
- Audio/Visual Recordings, 1977-1982; VI.
  This series contains recordings of performances and rehearsals. Materials are arranged alphabetically by title. Please note that the department does not have playback equipment for several of the formats.
  - Cassettes, 1.
    The audio/visual materials in this subseries are either in VHS or Umatic format.
    - Creativity with Bill Moyers: The Inventors, VHS (Cassette 1)
    - Iron Clad Agreement - AM Pittsburgh, U-matic (Cassette 2)
    - Iron Clad Agreement - WIS TV Interview, U-matic S (Cassette 3)
    - Gilded Age of Invention Demo Tape, 1982; U-matic (Cassette 4)
    - Oral History Drama Workshop - Hong Kong, VHS PAL Format (Cassette 5)
    - Westinghouse - Carnegie Mellon Campus Connection, July 1982; U-matic (Cassette 6)
    - Westinghouse - Public Version, 1981; U-matic (Cassette 7)
  - Films, 2.
    - Thomas Edison - Smithsonian Documentary with Iron Clad Agreement (Reel 1)
    - Iron Clad Agreement (Reel 2)
  - Video tape, 3.
    - Iron Clad Agreement - Dub Carnegie Mellon University / Allegheny Valley School, January 1977; Video tape on reel (Reel 3)
- Oversized and Ephemera, 1976-1981; VII.
  The oversized materials consist of posters, photographs, costumes, etc. The Mr. Flack Mask is a large hand-held mask used in the production of Out of This Furnace, which was made by Pittsburgh puppeteer Margo Lovelace.
  - The Amazing American Idea Factory poster (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Classroom Performance photograph (Folder 2)
  - Edison poster (Folder 3)
  - 57 by Two poster (Folder 4)
  - Gilded Age of Invention poster (Folder 5)
  - Gilded Age of Invention poster - Edinburgh Festival, 1977 (Folder 6)
  - Gilded Age of Invention Lincoln Center poster (Folder 7)
  - Interchangeable Parts Minds in Motion poster (Folder 8)
  - Ourselves Alone poster (Folder 9)
  - Out of This Furnace set design (Folder 10)
  - Out of This Furnace posters (Folder 11)
  - Virgins and Dynamos poster (Folder 13)
  - Virgins and Dynamos poster - UK Tour, 1981 (Folder 12)
  - Financial statements, 1976-1978 (Folder 14)
  - Costume - Jumpsuit (Folder 15)
  - Mr. Flack mask (Map-case 1, Drawer 5)
- Addendum
  This addendum series compiles the Iron Clad Agreement Company materials that were donated in 2015. The arrangement of the materials mirrors the arrangement of the original donation.
  - Operational Files
    - Iron Clad Rag Newsletter - Platform for Ideas
    - Programs
    - Promotional materials
    - Stationary
  - Playscripts
  - Photographs
  - Slides
    - Echoes from the Valley - Major Road Theatre Company American tour, 1984
    - Oral histroy workshops - Hong Kong, 1984
    - Sea-Change: The American Experience in Puerto Rico, 1928-1941 location shots - Puerto Rico, 1981-1982
    - Spring Tour - Connecticut, North Carolina, South Carolina, and Virginia, 1981
    - Summer Tour, 1980